<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swift on Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/swift/</link><description>Recent content in Swift on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a Basic Shopping Cart in Swift</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250423012001/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250423012001/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simplified shopping cart system in Swift. This is a common problem in many applications, especially e-commerce. We&amp;rsquo;ll model products, a cart, and basic functionalities like adding and removing items.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The core challenges here are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Modeling Products:&lt;/strong> Representing products with relevant information (name, price). We need a way to store this information in a structured manner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Managing the Cart:&lt;/strong> Maintaining a list of items in the cart and their quantities. We&amp;rsquo;ll need a data structure to efficiently add, remove, and track the total cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Calculating the Total:&lt;/strong> Accurately summing the prices of items in the cart, considering their quantities.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll leverage the following Swift features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swift String Reversal Tutorial</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409001013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409001013/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="swift-string-reversal-a-beginners-guide">Swift String Reversal: A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into a fundamental string manipulation task: reversing a string in Swift. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a simple palindrome checker, or need to display text in reverse order. Reversing a string is a core skill, and we&amp;rsquo;ll break it down step-by-step. We&amp;rsquo;ll create a function that takes a string as input and returns its reversed version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The primary challenge in reversing a string is understanding how to iterate through it in reverse order and reconstruct a new string with the characters in the reversed sequence. Swift&amp;rsquo;s strings are Unicode-correct, which means they aren&amp;rsquo;t simple arrays of ASCII characters. This has implications for performance and correctness.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>