<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 21:19:52 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 21:19:52 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mastering Array Chunking in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402221301/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402221301/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-array-chunking-in-javascript">Mastering Array Chunking in JavaScript&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re tackling a common JavaScript task: array chunking. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a website that displays a large number of images. Instead of loading all the images at once, which can slow down the page, you want to load them in smaller batches, or &amp;ldquo;chunks.&amp;rdquo; This approach, called lazy loading or pagination, enhances the user experience. We&amp;rsquo;ll write a function that takes an array and a chunk size as input, and returns a new array containing smaller arrays (chunks) of the specified size.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haskell - Implementing a Simple Caesar Cipher</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250403211404/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250403211404/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a classic cryptographic algorithm: the Caesar cipher. This cipher shifts each letter in a message by a fixed number of positions down the alphabet. While not secure, it provides a great way to learn about character manipulation and basic functional programming concepts in Haskell. We&amp;rsquo;ll take a plain text message and encrypt it using a key (the shift value), and also be able to decrypt back to the original message.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Text-Based Adventure Game in C++</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250404153041/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250404153041/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-a-simple-text-based-adventure-game-in-c">Building a Simple Text-Based Adventure Game in C++&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to embark on a journey to create a rudimentary text-based adventure game using C++. Imagine a scenario where the player is lost in a dark forest and needs to find their way out. The player will be presented with choices at each step, and their decisions will determine their fate. This project will introduce you to fundamental C++ concepts in a fun and engaging way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Word Counter in Go</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple word counter in Go. The program will take a string as input and return a map containing each unique word in the string and the number of times it appears. This is a common task in text analysis and data processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge here is to efficiently parse the input string, identify individual words, and keep track of their counts. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to handle:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Stack in Java</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250407001038/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250407001038/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="implementing-a-simple-stack-in-java">Implementing a Simple Stack in Java&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple Stack data structure in Java. A stack is a fundamental data structure that follows the Last-In, First-Out (LIFO) principle. Think of it like a stack of plates – you always take the top plate off first. We&amp;rsquo;ll create a stack that can store integers and includes basic operations like &lt;code>push&lt;/code>, &lt;code>pop&lt;/code>, &lt;code>peek&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>isEmpty&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Implementing a stack might seem straightforward, but it presents a few challenges:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Swift String Reversal Tutorial</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409001013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409001013/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="swift-string-reversal-a-beginners-guide">Swift String Reversal: A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into a fundamental string manipulation task: reversing a string in Swift. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a simple palindrome checker, or need to display text in reverse order. Reversing a string is a core skill, and we&amp;rsquo;ll break it down step-by-step. We&amp;rsquo;ll create a function that takes a string as input and returns its reversed version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The primary challenge in reversing a string is understanding how to iterate through it in reverse order and reconstruct a new string with the characters in the reversed sequence. Swift&amp;rsquo;s strings are Unicode-correct, which means they aren&amp;rsquo;t simple arrays of ASCII characters. This has implications for performance and correctness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working with Records in Haskell: Building a Simple Product Catalog</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409011813/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250409011813/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="working-with-records-in-haskell-building-a-simple-product-catalog">Working with Records in Haskell: Building a Simple Product Catalog&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to dive into Haskell records by building a simple product catalog. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building an e-commerce site. You need a way to represent products, each with a name, price, and a stock quantity. Haskell&amp;rsquo;s record syntax provides a clean and structured way to do this. We&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to define, create, and manipulate records to manage our product information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402024643/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402024643/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, I&amp;rsquo;m ready. How can I help you today? Please tell me what you&amp;rsquo;d like to do. For example, are you looking for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Information on a specific topic?&lt;/strong> (e.g., &amp;ldquo;What are the symptoms of the flu?&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Creative writing?&lt;/strong> (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Write a short poem about autumn.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Help with a task?&lt;/strong> (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Can you summarize this article for me?&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Code generation?&lt;/strong> (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Write a Python function to calculate the Fibonacci sequence.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Translation?&lt;/strong> (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Translate &amp;lsquo;hello&amp;rsquo; into Spanish.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Something else entirely?&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The more details you provide, the better I can assist you.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>