<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial on Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorial on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in Kotlin</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. Our goal is to write a function that can determine whether a given string is a palindrome, ignoring case and non-alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge of building a palindrome checker involves several considerations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Case Sensitivity:&lt;/strong> Palindromes should be case-insensitive. &amp;ldquo;Racecar&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome, and so is &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo;. We need to convert the input string to either lowercase or uppercase.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non-Alphanumeric Characters:&lt;/strong> Spaces, punctuation, and other non-alphanumeric characters should be ignored. &amp;ldquo;A man, a plan, a canal: Panama&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome if these characters are removed. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to filter these out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>String Reversal:&lt;/strong> We need an efficient way to compare the original string (after cleaning) with its reversed version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To tackle these challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the following Kotlin features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250420012436/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250420012436/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple palindrome checker in JavaScript. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward as forward (ignoring spaces, punctuation, and capitalization). Our goal is to create a function that takes a string as input and returns &lt;code>true&lt;/code> if it&amp;rsquo;s a palindrome and &lt;code>false&lt;/code> otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge lies in correctly comparing the input string to its reversed version. This involves several considerations:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Stack in TypeScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250415012045/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250415012045/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today we are going to implement a simple stack data structure in TypeScript. A stack is a fundamental data structure that follows the Last-In, First-Out (LIFO) principle. Imagine a stack of plates; you can only add or remove plates from the top. This tutorial will guide you through the process of creating a stack with essential functionalities like adding elements (push), removing elements (pop), and viewing the top element (peek).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Stack in C++</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250413024613/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250413024613/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today we are going to implement a simple stack data structure in C++ using an array as the underlying storage. A stack is a fundamental data structure that follows the Last-In, First-Out (LIFO) principle. This means the last element added to the stack is the first element removed. We will implement the core operations of a stack: &lt;code>push&lt;/code> (add an element), &lt;code>pop&lt;/code> (remove an element), and &lt;code>peek&lt;/code> (view the top element).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TypeScript Generics: Building a Reusable Data Mapper</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250410011803/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250410011803/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a reusable data mapper using TypeScript generics. Imagine you have different data structures coming from various APIs or databases, and you need to transform them into a unified, consistent format for your application. Writing a specific mapper for each data structure would be tedious and error-prone. Generics will allow us to create a flexible mapper that can handle various data types while maintaining type safety.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mastering Array Chunking in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402221301/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402221301/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mastering-array-chunking-in-javascript">Mastering Array Chunking in JavaScript&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re tackling a common JavaScript task: array chunking. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re building a website that displays a large number of images. Instead of loading all the images at once, which can slow down the page, you want to load them in smaller batches, or &amp;ldquo;chunks.&amp;rdquo; This approach, called lazy loading or pagination, enhances the user experience. We&amp;rsquo;ll write a function that takes an array and a chunk size as input, and returns a new array containing smaller arrays (chunks) of the specified size.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kotlin: Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. For instance, &amp;ldquo;madam&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo; are palindromes. Our goal is to create a function that takes a string as input and returns &lt;code>true&lt;/code> if it&amp;rsquo;s a palindrome, and &lt;code>false&lt;/code> otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge in implementing a palindrome checker lies in comparing the original string with its reversed version. We need to handle cases where the string contains uppercase and lowercase letters, and potentially ignore spaces or punctuation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Command Line Calculator in Haskell</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250422011934/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250422011934/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to implement a simple command-line calculator using Haskell. This calculator will take an expression as input (e.g., &amp;ldquo;2 + 3&amp;rdquo;) and output the result. This exercise will introduce us to parsing user input, handling potential errors, and performing basic arithmetic operations, all within the elegant framework of Haskell.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The creation of a command-line calculator introduces several challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parsing User Input:&lt;/strong> We need to take the string input provided by the user and transform it into a data structure that our program can understand and work with. This involves breaking down the input string into numbers and operators.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haskell - Implementing a Simple Caesar Cipher</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250403211404/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250403211404/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a classic cryptographic algorithm: the Caesar cipher. This cipher shifts each letter in a message by a fixed number of positions down the alphabet. While not secure, it provides a great way to learn about character manipulation and basic functional programming concepts in Haskell. We&amp;rsquo;ll take a plain text message and encrypt it using a key (the shift value), and also be able to decrypt back to the original message.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Text-Based Adventure Game in C++</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250404153041/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250404153041/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="building-a-simple-text-based-adventure-game-in-c">Building a Simple Text-Based Adventure Game in C++&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to embark on a journey to create a rudimentary text-based adventure game using C++. Imagine a scenario where the player is lost in a dark forest and needs to find their way out. The player will be presented with choices at each step, and their decisions will determine their fate. This project will introduce you to fundamental C++ concepts in a fun and engaging way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Word Counter in Go</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple word counter in Go. The program will take a string as input and return a map containing each unique word in the string and the number of times it appears. This is a common task in text analysis and data processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge here is to efficiently parse the input string, identify individual words, and keep track of their counts. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to handle:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Stack in Java</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250407001038/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250407001038/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="implementing-a-simple-stack-in-java">Implementing a Simple Stack in Java&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple Stack data structure in Java. A stack is a fundamental data structure that follows the Last-In, First-Out (LIFO) principle. Think of it like a stack of plates – you always take the top plate off first. We&amp;rsquo;ll create a stack that can store integers and includes basic operations like &lt;code>push&lt;/code>, &lt;code>pop&lt;/code>, &lt;code>peek&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>isEmpty&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Implementing a stack might seem straightforward, but it presents a few challenges:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Text-Based Adventure Game in Rust</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250424133141/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250424133141/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into Rust by building a simple text-based adventure game! This game will allow the user to navigate through a story by making choices, and the story will progress based on those choices. This is a great way to understand fundamental Rust concepts in a fun and engaging way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Creating a text-based adventure game presents several challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>User Input:&lt;/strong> We need to read input from the user, allowing them to choose actions or answer questions. Rust&amp;rsquo;s standard input/output library (&lt;code>std::io&lt;/code>) will be crucial here.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Game State:&lt;/strong> We need to maintain the current state of the game, such as the player&amp;rsquo;s location, inventory, and health. This requires using appropriate data structures like structs and enums.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Conditional Logic:&lt;/strong> The game&amp;rsquo;s narrative will branch based on the user&amp;rsquo;s choices. &lt;code>if&lt;/code>, &lt;code>else if&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>match&lt;/code> statements will be essential for implementing this branching logic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Output:&lt;/strong> We need to display information to the user, telling them about their surroundings, the consequences of their actions, and the current game state. We&amp;rsquo;ll use &lt;code>println!&lt;/code> for this.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>We will use these Rust features to tackle these challenges:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>