<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>String on Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/string/</link><description>Recent content in String on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/string/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in Kotlin</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. Our goal is to write a function that can determine whether a given string is a palindrome, ignoring case and non-alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge of building a palindrome checker involves several considerations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Case Sensitivity:&lt;/strong> Palindromes should be case-insensitive. &amp;ldquo;Racecar&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome, and so is &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo;. We need to convert the input string to either lowercase or uppercase.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non-Alphanumeric Characters:&lt;/strong> Spaces, punctuation, and other non-alphanumeric characters should be ignored. &amp;ldquo;A man, a plan, a canal: Panama&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome if these characters are removed. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to filter these out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>String Reversal:&lt;/strong> We need an efficient way to compare the original string (after cleaning) with its reversed version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To tackle these challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the following Kotlin features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250420012436/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250420012436/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple palindrome checker in JavaScript. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward as forward (ignoring spaces, punctuation, and capitalization). Our goal is to create a function that takes a string as input and returns &lt;code>true&lt;/code> if it&amp;rsquo;s a palindrome and &lt;code>false&lt;/code> otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge lies in correctly comparing the input string to its reversed version. This involves several considerations:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reversing a String in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250419011616/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250419011616/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to tackle a common string manipulation problem: reversing a string in JavaScript. This seemingly simple task offers a good opportunity to explore different coding styles and JavaScript features, and also highlights the importance of understanding immutability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Reversing a string might seem straightforward at first, but it presents a few challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Immutability:&lt;/strong> Strings in JavaScript are immutable. This means we cannot directly modify a string in place. We need to create a new string to hold the reversed version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Iteration:&lt;/strong> We need to iterate through the original string, extracting each character in the correct order for reversal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Building the Reversed String:&lt;/strong> We need a way to accumulate the reversed characters into a new string.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To solve these challenges, we will utilize the following JavaScript features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in JavaScript</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250412164914/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250412164914/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into a classic problem: building a palindrome checker in JavaScript. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward as forward (ignoring spaces, punctuation, and capitalization). Examples include &amp;ldquo;madam,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;racecar,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;A man, a plan, a canal: Panama.&amp;rdquo; We&amp;rsquo;ll write a function that determines whether a given string is a palindrome.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge with palindrome checking lies in pre-processing the input string. We need to:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kotlin: Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. For instance, &amp;ldquo;madam&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo; are palindromes. Our goal is to create a function that takes a string as input and returns &lt;code>true&lt;/code> if it&amp;rsquo;s a palindrome, and &lt;code>false&lt;/code> otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge in implementing a palindrome checker lies in comparing the original string with its reversed version. We need to handle cases where the string contains uppercase and lowercase letters, and potentially ignore spaces or punctuation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Simple Word Counter in Go</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250402025939/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple word counter in Go. The program will take a string as input and return a map containing each unique word in the string and the number of times it appears. This is a common task in text analysis and data processing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge here is to efficiently parse the input string, identify individual words, and keep track of their counts. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to handle:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>