<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arithmetic on Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/arithmetic/</link><description>Recent content in Arithmetic on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/arithmetic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a Simple Calculator in Python</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250427012447/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250427012447/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a simple calculator in Python. This calculator will take two numbers and an operator as input from the user, perform the corresponding arithmetic operation, and display the result. This exercise will help you solidify your understanding of input/output, basic arithmetic operations, and conditional statements in Python.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The main challenges in creating a calculator are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Taking User Input:&lt;/strong> We need to receive numbers and the operation from the user. We&amp;rsquo;ll use the &lt;code>input()&lt;/code> function to achieve this. Because &lt;code>input()&lt;/code> returns a string, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to convert the numerical inputs to the appropriate data type (float or int).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Performing Arithmetic Operations:&lt;/strong> We&amp;rsquo;ll need to handle the four basic arithmetic operations: addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. We&amp;rsquo;ll use the standard &lt;code>+&lt;/code>, &lt;code>-&lt;/code>, &lt;code>*&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>/&lt;/code> operators.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Handling Division by Zero:&lt;/strong> Division by zero is undefined. We need to check for this condition and prevent the program from crashing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Validating Input:&lt;/strong> The user might enter invalid inputs (e.g., non-numeric values, unsupported operators). We should gracefully handle these cases, informing the user about the error.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To address these challenges, we will use:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>