<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kotlin on Tutorial Island</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/kotlin/</link><description>Recent content in Kotlin on Tutorial Island</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tutorial-island.github.io/tags/kotlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker in Kotlin</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250425081710/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. Our goal is to write a function that can determine whether a given string is a palindrome, ignoring case and non-alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge of building a palindrome checker involves several considerations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Case Sensitivity:&lt;/strong> Palindromes should be case-insensitive. &amp;ldquo;Racecar&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome, and so is &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo;. We need to convert the input string to either lowercase or uppercase.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Non-Alphanumeric Characters:&lt;/strong> Spaces, punctuation, and other non-alphanumeric characters should be ignored. &amp;ldquo;A man, a plan, a canal: Panama&amp;rdquo; is a palindrome if these characters are removed. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to filter these out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>String Reversal:&lt;/strong> We need an efficient way to compare the original string (after cleaning) with its reversed version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>To tackle these challenges, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the following Kotlin features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kotlin: Implementing a Simple Palindrome Checker</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250421012248/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to implement a simple palindrome checker in Kotlin. A palindrome is a word, phrase, number, or other sequence of characters which reads the same backward or forward. For instance, &amp;ldquo;madam&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;racecar&amp;rdquo; are palindromes. Our goal is to create a function that takes a string as input and returns &lt;code>true&lt;/code> if it&amp;rsquo;s a palindrome, and &lt;code>false&lt;/code> otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge in implementing a palindrome checker lies in comparing the original string with its reversed version. We need to handle cases where the string contains uppercase and lowercase letters, and potentially ignore spaces or punctuation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kotlin: Implementing a Basic Data Validation Function</title><link>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250424233948/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tutorial-island.github.io/posts/article-20250424233948/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to build a simple data validation function in Kotlin. Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re receiving user input, and you need to ensure that certain fields, like age, are within a reasonable range. We&amp;rsquo;ll create a function that validates an age value and returns either the valid age or an error message.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="explanation">Explanation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The challenge here lies in handling potential errors. A user might enter a non-numeric value or an age that&amp;rsquo;s outside our allowed range (e.g., negative or excessively large). We need a mechanism to gracefully handle these scenarios without crashing our application.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>